floridarealtors.org 2008-11-18

# FAR - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Welcome to the Privacy Policy page of floridarealtors.org. Before we get to the meat and potatoes of this statement -- or the cookies and phish -- this policy is our promise to you saying, in 1,500 words or so, that we respect your privacy concerns. And we’ve evaluated our practices and procedures to protect your personal information. 

Information collection and use  
Floridarealtors.org is accessible to everyone, but only Florida Association of Realtor® (FAR) members may access certain tools and information. To view that info, FAR members must login if they wish to visit a page behind the firewall (a tech term for a data wall that you need a password to get around). We compare your login info to our membership records and the personal profiles. 

But here's the part that really, really matters: Your privacy is very important to us and we won't sell, share or rent this information to others, except in the ways outlined below. FAR collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site in order to verify valid users and is the sole owner of the information collected on this site.  
  
Registration  
You must be a member of FAR to access all areas of this Web site. 

Marketplace orders  
When you order a product from the Realtor Store, operated by Real Estate Industry Solutions LLC (REIS), a wholly-owned FAR subsidiary, we’ll need your name, street address (commercial or residential for delivery), telephone number, e-mail address and credit card information. The credit card info is for billing, or course, and we want the contact info so we can call or e-mail you if a question arises while we’re putting your order together. 

Security  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When you submit sensitive information through the Web site, your information is protected both online and off- line. When a registration/order form asks you for information such as credit card number, the info is encrypted (meaning it’s turned into a mess of useless data) before it leaves your computer. Once it arrives here, we have the code that can sort out the data, and we're the only ones with the code, which changes constantly. We use the encryption software SSL.

  If you have questions about security, send an e-mail to support@floridarealtors.org.   
  
Cookies  
Cookies are really good when your Mom makes them and they're fresh out of the oven and served with a glass of milk. But that's not important here. 

A cookie in the Internet world is a piece of data stored on your hard drive that has some connection to a Web site you visited. It generally contains info about you that makes it easier to visit that site. It could, for example, store your login information, which would save you time if you try to link to a password-protected section of floridarealtors.org since it already recognizes you as an FAR member. Cookies are pretty standard in the Internet industry, and a huge number of Web sites use them. Cookies also allow us to track visits to different areas of the site, which gives us a pretty nifty tool for figuring out which areas we should improve and expand, and which areas we should quietly allow to pass into history.

If you don't like being recognized, however, you can reject the cookie and remain absolutely anonymous. (Not to your family or friends, just us.) That may limit your use of a handful of areas on floridarealtors.org, though. In addition, third-party vendors produce some Web site services offered by floridarealtors.org. In those cases, the independent vendors may also place cookies on your hard drive. FAR has no control over these cookies.  
  
Sharing  
We do not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties, other than with our subsidiaries. We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers, but that info isn't linked to personal information that can identify you. We could tell another company, for example, that 85 percent of FloridaRealtors.org Web site visitors took our property insurance survey and here are the results, but we can't say that you clicked on the property insurance survey. (Even if you did.) 

We partner with other service providers to provide specific services. When you sign up for these FAR-sponsored services, we will share your name or other contact information, as necessary, to the third party that provides these services. Third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

Links  
This Web site contains links to other sites, but FAR is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. If another Web site asks for personal information, refer to that site's own privacy policy. FAR’s privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

Newsletter  
If you wish to subscribe to our association newsletters, we ask for contact information, such as name and e-mail address. We couldn’t deliver these products to you otherwise, right?   
  
Surveys   
Sometimes our site requests information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is voluntary and you may choose whether or not to disclose this information simply by not taking the survey. (Sometimes things are simple.) A survey could ask for information such as a name and address, as well as demographic information, such as your zip code or age. 

Choice/opt-out  
Florida Realtor members have the opportunity to "opt-out" of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our service providers, for example, you may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the e-mail, opting out through your Personal Profile page or sending an e-mail to Customer Support (support@floridarealtors.org).

Site and service updates   
Other types of e-mail correspondence don't have opt-out capabilities if you're an FAR member, such as the occasional notice of a major breaking news event to Florida licensees, e-mails sent to members of an FAR committee, and other Web site and service announcements, such as changes to a password to access IDX.  
  
Correction/updating personal information   
E-mail addresses, phone numbers and other personal information may be changed or updated by members in the "Personal Profile" section located in the membership area of the Web site.

Changes in this policy

In the future, FAR may need to change this privacy policy to meet the needs of its members; and since we can't predict the future, we must put this clause into the privacy policy: We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time. Such changes may be made without prior notice but will be explained in this privacy policy. Changes will be effective when posted. This privacy policy was last updated: Sept. 14, 2006.
